Niju Varughese

Philadelphia, PA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Niju-Varughese/83566212ec7a6326

Accomplished Licensed Pharmacist in Pennsylvania, New Jersey, and Texas with PharmD degree and strong experience providing top-quality pharmacy services. Excellent interpersonal skills establishing positive relationships with customers, pharmaceutical manufacturers and representatives, medical professionals, healthcare organizations, insurance providers and company staff. Proficient in mentoring and managing diverse teams to provide quality care and accurate medication dispensing.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Clinical Pharmacist

Amerihealth Mercy - Philadelphia, PA - July 2012 to Present

Responsible for reviewing Prior Authorization cases and rendering coverage determinations based on clinical criteria and plan design.

- Handles calls and correspondence from providers and respond to inquiries, complaints and reconsiderations.
- Reviews members' medication profiles and makes recommendations to health care providers based on evidence based medicine and national guidelines.

STAFF PHARMACIST

MEDCO - Willingboro, NJ - January 2008 to July 2012

Ensured pharmacy prior authorization and managed care were consistent with covered benefits, quality of care and medical necessity.

- Assessed drug therapy in relation to patient's current drug therapy, known allergies and age appropriateness.
- Reviewed prescriptions for completeness, appropriate indication dosing and duration of therapy.
- Contacted prescribers for change in therapy or verification of therapy.

Staff Pharmacist/ Pharmacy Manager

Target - Plymouth Meeting, PA - March 2007 to January 2008

Responsible for pharmacy productivity and profitability.

- Coached and trained team members to achieve service and sales goals.
- Counseled patients on prescription and over-the-counter medications and provided guidance regarding related questions.
- Established productive working relationships with other store areas.

Staff Pharmacist

COSTCO - Township of Brick, NJ - July 2003 to March 2007

Supervised pharmacy technicians and reviewed the prescription data entry and order-filling accuracy.

- Consulted and advised patients on prescriptions and over-the-counter medications and provided guidance improving quality of life.
- Interpreted physicians' prescriptions and consulted with them regarding drug-to-drug interactions and adverse events

EDUCATION

Doctor of Pharmacy in ACTIVE LICENSES = Pennsylvania Pharmacist License No. RP441461 valid till September 2014 = New Jersey Pharmacist License No. RI028912 valid till April 2013 Authorization to Adminster Injectables PA RP1006287 valid 9/2014 RUTGERS UNIVERSITY - Ernesto Mario School of Pharmacy

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

TECHNICAL TRAINING

Proficient in PDX, ARGUS, CONDOR, RUMBA, PERFORM PA, SYMPHONY, ESD, WEBTOOL